How to control your mind when you feel depressed
Hello.
I'm so glad to see you in person after seeing you only on TV.
You're a student and watch TV instead of studying?
I have two concerns.
I am very happy.
Everything is going really good.
But every once in a while, I feel depressed.
Once I get pessimistic like this, I keep sinking into
more negative thoughts. How should I control my mind at those times?
At those times, think, "Ah, I am pessimistic again. I'll keep on sinking,
and this can only harm me" Be aware like this.
Ah, I see…
What's the first thing to do? Think, "Oh, I am sinking deeply into negative thoughts."
"If I don't stop, this will become depression. This can only harm me."
Become aware like this. This is called self-awareness.
When you fall, what should you be aware of? Be aware that you've fallen and you get up.
When you're sinking, be aware that you're sinking and come out of it.
Don't think about how you cannot be sinking. Instead be aware when you are sinking and come out of it.
If you've fallen, be aware that you've fallen and get up.
So, if you have this tendency, quickly become aware of it when it happens.
Think, "Oh, I'm starting to think negatively, again."
If you don't catch it, you'll sink further.
If you become aware, you'll snap out of it.
My second concern is this.
I'm in the 9th grade, about to advance to high school.
Because of the grading schedule, my final semester ends earlier.
It ends in early November, so 4 months of free time.
During that time, I can study or play,
but I want to learn a new sport instead.
I've played ball sports,
so I want to try combative sport.
Like Judo, boxing, or kick boxing.
But my parents are strongly against it.
They say to me, "Are you crazy? Why would you learn low class sport like fighting?"
They also tell me
"You should be studying during that time, so how are you going to study?"
But I've been studying and exercising all through middle school, and my grades are pretty good.
But, because my older brother gets really good grades,
my parents are unhappy with mine.
So my parents think that I can't study and exercise at the same time.
But I am confident that I can do both.
I really want to learn a combative spot, so how can I persuade my parents?
Go ahead and do it. I will give you permission to do it.
If you can, try judo. Judo is less combative.
Among the things you mentioned, kickboxing is the most combative.
But my parents won't let me,
and I can't do it without their financial support.
If they won't let you, then you can't do it.
Why? Because you're still a minor.
Since it is not your money,
you can't do whatever you want.
Talk to your mother, and, if she lets you do it, then you can. But if she doesn't, then you can't.
Oh... Is that so?
It can't be helped.
Why? World cannot be all as you want it to be.
Or reach a compromise with your mother.
Tell her that you will study harder, you will clean house everyday, or you will cook everyday.
You have to pay somehow for it
since it is their money.
Since you can't pay them back with money, you can pay them with something else.
Trying like this is okay.
Also, you're not your brother, right?
If your brother becomes a monk, will you become a monk too?
Will you study hard because your brother studies hard or not study because your brother is not studying?
Your mother compares you with your brother because you are all living together.
But there is no need to feel belittled by it.
When you become a parent yourself, and your younger child studies hard while the older doesn't,
you would tell the older child to study hard like his brother.
Or vice versa, if the younger brother studies harder.
You can get hurt by the words, but there's no need to
because your parent don't mean to hurt your feelings.
It's good to do what you want, but you can't make the final decision.
Why? Because you're still a minor.
If you were born to poor and uneducated parents like me,
you can do whatever you want.
I did whatever I wanted at the time
because my parents didn't know where I was going or what I was doing.
Your parents telling you what to do mean they are smart
Do you prefer smart parents or ignorant parents?
Smart parents.
Since your parents are smart, you have to deal with the consequences of their interventions.
Okay.
Although you can voice your opinion, you can't make all the decisions because you are still a minor.
What happens once you turn 20?
Who can make all the decisions?
Me.
Yes, it is you. You have to be patient until then.
How many more years to wait?
3 more years.
Until then, you need to compromise.
don't always be stubborn,
and make some effort like giving her a back massage.
If that doesn't work, there's nothing you can do about it. Do you understand?
Yes.
I can't convince your parents for you here
because you parents are your guardians.
This is how things are.
It's okay. Give it a try.
Okay. Thank you!